start with a right triangle with lengths
a b and c create four congruent copies
of such triangle arrange the congruent
triangles to form a square the empty
yellow square has a side length of C
arrange the congruent triangles so that
they look exactly like the yellow Square
the small red square has a side length
of B minus a the area of the four
triangles is 12 a b * 4 plus the area of
the small red square which is the square
of B minus a
these are all equal to the area of the
yellow Square which is c² 12 of ab * 4
becomes 2ab plus the expansion of the
square of B minus a which is square of a
- 2 a + b² = c² 2 a and -2ab is 0 so the
resulting equation is square of a + b² =
c² this is the Pythagorean theorem